Christopher Bonner

LinkedIn, Portfolio, christopher.bonner@outlook.com

Diligent computer science student with 2 years of experience in live digital projects involving Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Digital Skills Consulting. In previous roles I have, managed teams, presented and created backend APIs with Python. I am familiar with frontend design and development using React JS and I am in the process of learning cloud computing technologies from AWS. In my personal time I bolster my technical skills by participating in Udemy courses and I participate in virtual work experience with companies like JP Morgan.

SKILLS

- Proficient in MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) Outlook
- Programming Languages: Python, Visual Basic, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Frameworks: Flask, ReactSource Control: Git, GitHub
- Database: SQL, MySQL
- Presentation
- Project Management
- Organisation
- Collaboration

Work Experience / Live Projects

AWS Digital Skills Project 2024

Birmingham

Mentor

December 2023-March 2024

I am again participating in the AWS Digital Skills Project but this time as a mentor. These are the requirements of being a mentor:

- I am responsible for the team's success.
- I directly assist the project manager of the team.
- I teach and advise the team like helping with the designs and programming.

Advanced Software
Group Task
Birmingham
October 2023

For tech week 2023 I was selected to go to Advanced Computer Software. They educated us and made us present about an innovative ai solution.

- We discussed the impact of using AI in software solutions.
- I was tasked with designing an IT solution that incorporates AI for a key sector. For me I chose education.
- We then presented our solution to key employers including Microsoft and Advanced.

East Village Birmingham
Public Relations October 2023

For tech week 2023 I was tasked with reporting upon various tech events in Birmingham City Centre. Responsibilities included:

- Handling public relations during Birmingham Tech Week 2023.
 - I Took hundreds of pictures and videos at 10 different tech events.
 - I Participated in technology events at BT and HSBC.

AWS Digital Skills Project 2023

Birmingham

Project Manager

December 2022-March 2023

In this project we were tasked with designing and developing a solution which will assist students with getting part time jobs. I was appointed project manager for the group and handled the backend programming.

- I handled the backend programming for the solution in Python and gathered thousands of job listings.
- I created documents such as Gantt charts, Project plans, and Minutes.
- We presented to over 20 employers and 3 colleges, including, AWS, BBC, Hays.
- I won the student of the year award for BMet College.

Employment History

Five Guys Birmingham

Crew Member December 2022–Present

- I learned how to prepare and cook on 4 different stations.
- I developed relationships with customers to ensure that they had a great experience.
- Catered for customers with allergies and ensured that their food was not being cross-contaminated.
- I have achieved employee of the month for 2 months in a row.

Asda Birmingham

Porter November 2022

- I cleaned up the trollies on the car park and was responsible for multiple bays.
- I answered various customer queries ensuring a good customer experience.
- I assisted customers with disabilities by catering for them.

EDUCATION

BMet Matthew Boulton College

Birmingham

Pearson BTEC Level 3 National Extended Diploma in Information Technology

September 2022-August 2024

Predicted: D*D*D

Barr Beacon School Birmingham

9 GCSE's including English Literature: 5, English Language: 8, Maths: 8, Chemistry: 7, Physics: 6, Biology: 6, Computer Science: 8, IT: Distinction.

September 2017-August 2022

References available upon request.